<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ian&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ian&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:56:52 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Titan Dev Diary #8</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:56:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-8/</guid>
      <description>Day 8 Stomping the final UI thing didn&amp;rsquo;t take too long.
I used pdb, Pythons debugging module, for the first time; which was exciting! Typically I spray prints all over the place
and figure out the issue. However I felt I needed the stack for figuring
out the event loop. It&amp;rsquo;s quite cool, and a lot different then the IDE
debugging I&amp;rsquo;m used to, but still simple and informative. Onto the network!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titan Dev Diary #7</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:59:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-7/</guid>
      <description>Day 7 Commit Hash: a1f55212d407076b77610eec374f20b8f86b89ca
Completed all the UI features. One can split the army, muster new units, and resolve battles. Points will be granted
to the victor, and the UI updates accordingly. One final visual
glitch is present, and once I finally chase that down, it&amp;rsquo;s on to
transmitting data around.
I both think this will be simple and hard. There&amp;rsquo;s definitely some
thinking I&amp;rsquo;ll have to throw into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titan Dev Diary #6</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 14:50:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-6/</guid>
      <description>Day 6 Commit Hash: e873ea2a82e09165a8a6297977f0698169e0e854
I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly brushed the rust off my Object-Oriented programming for Python. Refactored code to have classes coresponding to the current action, as opposed to lumping them all into one area. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter so much on the UI side but easier
from a development perspective.
The Breakdown
Features Added:
 Resolve battle now updates Overview Correctly A &amp;ldquo;Turn&amp;rdquo; function is in-process: will guide a player through valid actions per army.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titan Dev Diary #5</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-5/</guid>
      <description>Day 5 Commit Hash: 83f45e68913d98b37de982954d3af609d3af9788
Iteratively hitting walls, walking down wrong paths, but still finding a way forward. I understand tkinter enough to be my own guiding light. At points of hard contention I&amp;rsquo;d beseech external resources only to find I&amp;rsquo;d independently implemented their sage suggestions. This happened ad nauseam multiple times giving rise to new tantilizing perceptions of my abilities: either simple things bamboozle me or I&amp;rsquo;m at the bleeding edge of a problem space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titan Dev Diary #4</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 14:49:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-4/</guid>
      <description>Day 4 Commit Hash: baea475c7ccb548842ecc022ec44c8e05fd7e444
No significant stumbling blocks, other then stumbling from fatigue. I got mustering &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo;; the unit list doesn&amp;rsquo;t refresh unless you close-reopen.
Also the main overview doesn&amp;rsquo;t update accordingly.
I refactored Characters/Creatures - Titan calls them &amp;lsquo;Characters&amp;rsquo;, I like &amp;lsquo;Creatures&amp;rsquo;,
but lets be real in code I need to call them units -to use a csv and a namedtuple. The writing of took 5 minutes, and troubleshooting took 40.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titan Dev Diary #3</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 14:49:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-3/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 Commit Hash: 28d4de8ac878570bca991ccc63e3eead3fdaea23
Made a lot of progress, however one measures progress when &amp;ldquo;finished&amp;rdquo; is of nebulous
determination. It&amp;rsquo;s ugly as sin but the UI is there for Opponents and Players, and
also a pop out menu for the Player Armies. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if prettifying is ever a thing.
Now I need to make the central feature of splitting one army into two.
A quick search before sign-off reveals that tkinter doesn&amp;rsquo;t explicitly support drag-drop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titan Dev Diary #2</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 02:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-2/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 Commit: ad3e49bb532ebca99a332defa2a84e9b230f9e00 This was the day where I bit off more than I could chew. Or at least I felt that way. When I don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand something, it can feel daunting.
I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how tkinter was behaving or would behave between multiple window states.
 How would information flow between different client-side components of the GUI? How would I maintain state of the other players? How would each player get a GUI element in the same app but update discretely?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titan Dev Diary #1</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 23:48:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-1/</guid>
      <description>[Project Repo|https://github.com/ianbruyere/titan-army-tracker]
Day 1 Commit: ad3e49bb532ebca99a332defa2a84e9b230f9e00
Now I&amp;rsquo;m on my own; I&amp;rsquo;m beyond the scope of the blog post. I floundered for a bit on where to start; feverishly typing out ideas as a balm. My starting point though has been determined: the setup screen.
What a session this turned out to be.
I made headway quickly getting dropdowns created, populated, and an image loaded in. With the basic elements in place, the stage was set for trouble to manifest:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titan Dev Diary #0</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 14:50:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/titan-dev-diary-0/</guid>
      <description>Background Titan(1980) is a fun board game with significant flaws.
Some flaws charming, some unwieldly. With digital aid Titan can rise above.
Making army movement easier, distributing public army information,
and doing bookeeping will be the main goals. Additional
benefits are preserving game state since Titan can last
upwards of 4 hours, takes significant table real estate,
and relocating is tenous at best.
Day -1 I made some false starts since my original vision was for a phone app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pivot</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 18:59:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-23/</guid>
      <description>My writing is undergoing tectonic shifts;
Rearranging around more granular, ad-hoc insights. I like the idea of a developement diary.
Some other categories brewing as well to structure around.
Hopefully nothing too abstract or unrelatable.
We&amp;rsquo;ll see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #22</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 23:47:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-22/</guid>
      <description>Pacing. A core tenant of learning, or maybe more of one of it&amp;rsquo;s dials. When to charge forward simply gaining experience and when to examine the broken pieces around you as you rebuild the fractured machinery: a little bit old, a little bit new, skewed to your own purpose.
The above writing is to mask the fact that I did nothing in way of coding or computers this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #21</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 23:47:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-21/</guid>
      <description>Nothing in the cooker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #20</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 23:51:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-20/</guid>
      <description>Sadly a dud week in the productivity department; I feel about due to churning again though. But in some ways this give&amp;rsquo;s me an opportunity to speak about commitment.
It&amp;rsquo;d be nice if every single post was overflowing with the bounty of my endeavors, but I simply don&amp;rsquo;t see that happening. I have a job, people I care about, other hobbies, and strong desires at times to simply sit back and let the world spin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #19</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 23:21:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-19/</guid>
      <description>Wow. Instruction is hard. Mad respect to anyone who can teach anything and even one person get&amp;rsquo;s one they are saying. I attempted to teach a friend the basics of coding. A surprising nodule of difficulty was making sure I&amp;rsquo;d covered all the bases of assignment.
After consulting the general lesson layout of other beginner tutorials assignment seemed as good a starting place as any. However as I wrote later sections I returned to that lesson time and time again to ensure that proper foundations and understanding was there for later concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #18</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 23:49:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-18/</guid>
      <description>Life busy this week. I am preparing an informal bootcamp on coding for some of my friends this weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with teaching coding. I&amp;rsquo;m not good at it but through my own constant learning(and discovering of pitfalls) I try and pass it on to other people I know. Teaching is for everyone; people might say you have to have a knack for it, and I don&amp;rsquo;t discount that being naturally disposed towards certain personality traits are a plus - patience, understanding, empathy come to mind - but teaching is simply good communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #17</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 23:18:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-17/</guid>
      <description>I learned the power of Perl this week . I was writing a script to move some text files between servers, and a co-worker showed me how with bash as the frame and a perl one-liner doing the lifting he could accomplish what was taking me ~15 lines of Python. A lesson in the quick and clean writing of scripts; needless to say I was impressed.
For the curious it was something like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #16</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 23:27:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-16/</guid>
      <description>I get my stuff done, test it but boneheaded mistakes have a way of creeping in.
I could try and justify it: a new process, not entirely sure of the common checks you learn when something becomes routine; but the reality is my behavior towards development needs changing. Mistakes are costly from a time perspective, especially when priorties have shifted away from development and towards validation and release.
I&amp;rsquo;m learning to be a little slower with my development; it&amp;rsquo;ll save me time and hassle in the long run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #15</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 23:40:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-15/</guid>
      <description>So&amp;hellip;again I had to troubleshoot this Hugo site. For some reason all my local changes got overwritten. And my backup situation was less than ideal. Managed to preserve all my posts and their timestamps, but as the result of 5 hours of work. Not fun. But done and if this happens in the future should be able to reinstate much easier.
Keeping the flame of the weekly commit alive.
The Doing Starting to learn some Linux Admin Stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #14</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 23:38:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-14/</guid>
      <description>I don’t have anything I’m making any huge waves on. I’ve got some things brewing in the back of my mind in terms of fun projectsm but no action.
Rather I’ve been thinking over how much of programming - and life in general - is mainly talking. My new(ish) job has tons of meetings, more than my previous experience. And at first, it was galling: I was constantly thinking “When are these meetings going to end so I can do the real work”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #13</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 23:29:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-13/</guid>
      <description>Still not much popping off this week.
This is more a placeholder until I get some mojo back. I at least don’t want to lose the fact that I’m consistently posting even if content is lacking.
Life is happening so I can’t neglect that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #12</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 22:26:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-12/</guid>
      <description>The Weekly Commit has hit a low tide this week.
The Doing Mainly quality of life things for the computer, no real coding. I believe businesses call it infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #11</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 22:24:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-11/</guid>
      <description>Again not too much going on. Just plugging away.
The Doing Continuing to at code on my own once a week. This week I stubbed out some data processing on a weightlifting spreadsheet I’ve been updating for some years now. Eventually it will be full-flegded with graphing and filters and packaged in it’s own Jupyter notebook but for now: cleaning and enforcing data-entry.
Learning Still committing to the 20 minutes of learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #10</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 22:55:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-10/</guid>
      <description>Nothing too much in the meta today.
The Doing  Used RegEx casually. An exoctic feeling since I used to actively avoid RegEx; I still need StackOverflow - and a testbed - it’s still RegEx after all but I understand the methodoloy and can write basic blocks without reference.  The Learning I’ve decicded to reboot my Theoretical learning starting with mathematics. My goal is low-level commitment, emphasis on commit: 20 minutes a day is all I’m going for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #9</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 21:34:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-9/</guid>
      <description>The Weekly Commit is a bit of a misnomer right now since I’m not committed to anything. A bit all over the place this week, from trying out the Android ecosystem to Bluetooth.
I chart my path by not having one.
The Doing  attempted to find the local database on a phone that contained training data I wanted  I wasn’t succesful, and most resources I googled assumed the app was my own proect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #8</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 22:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-8/</guid>
      <description>Python is becoming easier. Building quick and dirty tools to accomplish busy work are at my fingertips instead of buried in documentation. Now coding is even more fun because I can play around on my own. Bash scripting is getting there too; some syntax throws me(brackets for conditionals…really!?) but I’m getting there. The feedback of finishing these small tasks keeps that addictive question “What else can I do?” on loop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #7</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 20:41:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-7/</guid>
      <description>I spotted a wild Big O application!; exciting as I’ve only experienced it in a controlled-environment. I’ll post the outline here so knowledgeable people can say how close(or far off) I was.
Naive for i in x: for j, k in enumerate(y): if i == k: result.append(i) More Performant at Scale(Big O) for i in x: index = 0 for j, k in enumerate(y): if i == k: index = j result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #6</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 23:45:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-6/</guid>
      <description>As a continuation of last week: deleting the old gcc files had no detrimental effect on my computer. However, hugo this time(since now I don&amp;rsquo;t trust brew) was a bit of pain. Now I think it&amp;rsquo;s all sorted and honestly, learned even more about the Linux shell environment. I&amp;rsquo;m a young whippersnapper when it comes to Linux and in a lot of ways computers in general, so I&amp;rsquo;m not tearing through the shell ripping apart build processes or anything like that&amp;hellip;yet; Linux can be as wild as you want but I&amp;rsquo;m glad I can take it at my own pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #5</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 23:20:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-5/</guid>
      <description>The Doing Debugging my system. Something strange was happening when my python venv were suddenly not finding any installed packages-e.g. gym not found- and when I tried to install them with pip&amp;hellip;it failed with the longest and most unhelpful error I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. So I switch to my main project thinking it&amp;rsquo;s maybe just a problem with the one venv(only switching AFTER I tried to remake the venv, reinstall the package, run the thing etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #4</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 23:21:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-4/</guid>
      <description>My coding endeavors are in a state of drift: whatever grabs my attention for a brief burst before I turn to the next shiny thing. I take it as my natural bounty of finally being employed: enjoying coding instead of a method of &amp;ldquo;getting employed&amp;rdquo;; every time I sat down to code in my unemployed state I&amp;rsquo;d be pursuing:
A) enticing employers with my knowledge of buzz words
B) shoring up theoretical weaknesses given my lack of &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; education i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #3</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 23:18:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-3/</guid>
      <description>The Doing I wrote some bash scripts: one that uses sed/awk to find null data giving the option to scrub it, and another that goes through a series of logs and outputs the desired information to console.
Learning Learning what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing: awk/sed/grep and bash scripting, the fine art of using and analyzing the tools.
Near Future Goals Haven&amp;rsquo;t exactly been knocking any of these off my to-do lists. Happy with the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m making self-started endeavors to code a bit every week(outside of work) but haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to focus on any of my major goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #2</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 23:22:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-2/</guid>
      <description>The Doing Not too much doing. The crush of Christmas and New Years being what it is. Mainly finding the threads of where I left off in my own code. Mainly in the testing section, simply need to remember where I was questing.
Learning Did some brief overview of security stuff. Mainly laying down some lead lines for future(far off) endeavors. Nothing much.
Near-Future Goals About the same. Start on my project in earnest as time and sanity allows, also keep up with my own small projects as buffers against code-block and staleness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Commit #1</title>
      <link>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 21:31:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianbruyere.github.io/posts/the-weekly-commit-1/</guid>
      <description>The Doing Made a CLI in python to process some Personal Training Data. It&amp;rsquo;s standard as dataprocessing goes: input a csv, clean it, outputs interesting information in csv. Other than being practically useful for myself, it allowed me to scrape the rust off my Python. The Python Standard Library is vast, and my goal of having it close at hand is only possible through constant practice. Suddenly having full-time work day disrupted my rhythm; doing some personal coding is a sign I haven&amp;rsquo;t lost the beat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
